Hello everyone and welcome back
to English Pod, my name is Marco.
And my name is Catherine
and today we have an
elementary level lesson
for you guys out there.
That's right.
Today we are going to
talk about an interesting
topic, especially for women,
we are going to the nail salon.
Oh, okay.
So we're going to get
our finger nails painted.
All right.
So let's take a look at vocabulary
preview to find out what nail salon means.
Alright, so if you
go to a nail salon, it's
a specific place where
they paint your nails, right?
Exactly.
So it's a shop or a store where
you can have your nails painted.
So they have special people to help you.
If you want to go get your hair
cut, you would go to the hair salon.
Exactly.
So we have hair salon and nail salon.
In this case, the nail salon,
they can't cut your hair.
Okay.
Very good.
Why don't we listen to our
dialogue for the first time?
Honey, I'll be right back.
Where are you going?
I told you already.
I'm going to get my nails done.
Again, you just went last week.
You spend more time at the nail
salon than you do here at home.
Honestly, why do you need
to manic your every week?
Well, first of all, I like to pump
them myself and my nails look great.
You should come with me.
Why?
I don't want to have nail
polish or anything like that.
They don't only paint my nails.
The manicurists will
remove my cuticles, file
my nails, and apply at
least four coats of nail polish.
Yeah.
Sounds like something
I should definitely do.
All right, we're back.
So now we found some very interesting
and specific words related to nails.
So why don't we look at those
now on language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
All right.
So this first word is
an important word for
every woman to know, and I
know a lot of men who get this too.
It's called a manicure.
All right.
Manicure.
And what exactly is a manicure?
Well, a manicure is a service
that you get at a nail salon.
And that means that
the people at the nail
salon will cut your nails
and shape your nails.
It means if you want
them to be pointy or
boxy, and then you get
them painted and dried.
OK.
So they basically take care of your
nails, of your fingernails, a manicure.
Exactly.
And so the important thing to remember
here that a manicure is for your hands.
Right.
So you can also get your toenails
or your feet taken care of, right?
Exactly.
So that's different.
That's a pedicure.
Because peda means foot.
So pedicure is for your feet,
and a manicure is for your hands.
All right.
Very good.
And well, we talked
about painting your nails
and that paint has a
specific name, right?
Exactly.
So you wouldn't use wall paint
on your fingers, would you?
Right.
So you have to use a special
paint, and this is called nail polish.
Nail polish.
OK.
So a polish is something that
makes a surface or a thing shiny.
OK.
So nail polish is a paint that
makes your nails very shiny.
All right.
Very good.
Moving on, we talked
about a manicure and there's
a specific word for the
person that provides
this service that takes
care of your nails.
OK.
So the job at a nail salon is manicureists.
That's the person who paints your nails.
OK.
All right.
And so you could say, I
have a favorite manicureist.
Her name is Sally.
OK.
Very good.
And well, manicureists,
they perform a manicure
and will apart from
painting your nails.
They also push your cuticles or
remove your cuticles like in the dialogue.
What are the cuticles?
OK.
Cuticle is a very hard word.
This word describes the
skin around your fingernail.
OK.
So you have skin all over your body.
But on your fingernail,
you have special kind of skin.
And so a manicureist will
sometimes push or cut the dead skin.
That's the cuticle from your finger.
OK.
Very good.
Get your fingernails now.
You will see a little thin
layer of skin on your fingernail.
That's the cuticle.
And well, apart from
removing your cuticles and
painting your nails, they
will also file your nails.
And this is a verb to file.
To file.
OK.
So this is a word that's
kind of like cut or trim.
But a file is a more delicate process.
So it means that we kind of shave
off very, very, very little at a time.
And so to file your nails means to make
them shaped differently or to smooth them.
They're not cutting.
It's not that.
It's a little bit less than that.
And now there's also a
noun for this, a nail file.
And most women will usually have it.
It's a long piece of cardboard that
has a paper that's kind of like
sand on it, kind of like sand paper.
It doesn't feel good when
you rub it with your hand.
With your hand.
But if you use it on your nails,
it will little by little just take
away little parts of your nail.
Yeah.
And like that, you usually
see it in the many secretaries,
you know, in TV shows,
they're always filing their nails.
Exactly.
And making them perfect.
OK.
So those are the words we
have for language takeaway.
Why don't we take a
look at our dialogue again?
And we'll be back in a little bit.
Honey, I'll be right back.
Where are you going?
I told you already.
I'm going to get my nails done.
Again, you just went last week.
You spend more time at the nails
salon than you do here at home.
Honestly, why do you
need a manicure every week?
Well, first of all, I like
to pump them myself.
And my nails look great.
You should come with me.
Why? I don't want to have
nail polish or anything like that.
They don't only paint my nails.
The manicureists will remove my cuticles,
file my nails, and apply at
least four coats of nail polish.
Yeah.
Sounds like something
I should definitely do.
All right, we're back.
So now, why don't we
start with some phrases,
some very good phrases that we
found in this dialogue in Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
This first place is really
important when we talk about nails
because it's the way that we
describe going to the nail salon.
So I can say, I'm going
to get my nails done today.
OK, so to get your nails done, that means
that you're going to get your
nails cut, filed, painted, et cetera.
I'm going to get a manicure.
But that's very, I don't know, I'm serious.
So you could say, I'm
going to get my nails done.
It's more spoken language.
OK, so I'm going to get my nails done.
Or you got your nails done, very good.
And well, the woman was talking
about why she likes to go get a manicure.
And she said that she
likes to pamper herself.
OK, this is very common,
especially when women
are trying to talk about why they spend
money on hair and nails and clothes.
They say, I like to pamper myself.
The pamper means to treat very, very well.
OK, so if you go get
a manicure, it's kind of
like pampering yourself
or maybe going to a spa.
Exactly, or getting a massage.
And so we could say
also, don't pamper the dog.
He's very naughty.
So a synonym would be to spoil.
To spoil oneself.
To pamper.
Indulge.
OK, so, and well, she was talking
about how they perform a manicure.
And she talked about
four coats of nail polish.
So a coat, we know that
it's kind of like a jacket, right?
But in this case-- In this
case, it means a layer.
So you paint your nails one time.
OK, you have color.
Maybe it doesn't look right.
OK, it's very thin.
So you say, OK, I'm
going to paint two coats.
And then you paint one more time.
And the color gets darker.
And you paint one more time.
And the color gets
very dark and very thick.
And so these are called coats.
That means layers of nail polish.
And that's the special where we use.
We're talking about painting our nails.
Right, so it's not only for
nails, but if you're painting
your house, maybe you need
two or three coats of paint.
Exactly, if we have a red wall
and we want to paint it white,
we definitely need two, three,
maybe four coats of paint.
Otherwise, we'll still see the red.
OK, very good.
Very interesting phrases.
Let's take a look at this
dialogue for the very last time.
And we'll be back shortly.
Honey, I'll be right back.
Where are you going?
I told you already, I'm
going to get my nails done.
Again, you just went last week.
You spend more time at the nail
salon than you do here at home.
Honestly, why do you
need a manicure every week?
Well, first of all, I
like to pamper myself.
And my nails look great.
You should come with me.
Why?
I don't want to have nail
polish or anything like that.
They don't only paint my nails.
The manicureists will remove my cuticles,
file my nails, and apply at
least four coats of nail polish.
Yeah, sounds like something
I should definitely do.
All right, we're back.
So Catherine, are you
a big fan of manicures?
Do you get it done often?
I didn't use to, but I
really enjoy them now.
I think it's a nice way
to relax on the weekends.
So every couple of weeks,
I go to the nail salon.
And I have my nails done.
All right.
And I think one of the words
that we didn't talk about here,
but it's very, I don't know, for
men, it's kind of a strange smell.
It's nail polish remover.
They pass its own, right?
It's a very strong chemical.
It is really disgusting.
Nail polish remover, you know, the
word to remove means to take away.
And so when the nail polish, we want
to change the color, we have to use this.
It's like water, but it smells really bad.
And so my boyfriend always
gets angry when I use the nail
polish remover because the
whole house starts to stink.
It's a very strong smell,
and you get kind of dizzy.
So that's what it's like.
Yeah, it goes into your head.
All right, well, if you guys have any
questions, any doubts or any suggestions
about this lesson or any other lesson,
please come to our website EnglishPod.com.
And we'll see you guys there.
Bye, everyone.
Bye.
[MUSIC PLAYING]